szul.com 2014-11-30

# Szul.com - Privacy Policy

##  Privacy Policy 

###  **The TRUSTe Program**

**Szul Jewelry, Inc.** is a licensee of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build users' trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because this web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. By displaying the TRUSTe trustmark, this web site has agreed to notify you of:

  * What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personal identification is collected from you through the web site 
  * The organization collecting the information 
  * How the information is used 
  * With whom the information may be shared 
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information 
  * The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under **Szul.com** control 
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact our customer service department at [customerservice@szul.com](mailto:customerservice@szul.com). If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe [ http://www.truste.org/users/users_watchdog.html](http://www.truste.org/users/users_watchdog.html). TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with the Web site to resolve your concerns.

###  **Privacy Statement**

Effective on: (05/25/04)  
Szul offers a written privacy policy to inform customers about the type of information we collect, why we collect it, how it is processed, and with whom it may be shared. 

We respect the value of all personal information that you share with us. We appreciate the fact that you are showing us your trust and confidence, and we promise to live up to your expectations at all times. We will use your personal information only to improve your shopping experience on the site, and **we will not share your information** with any outside parties, except as outlined in this privacy statement (see "Third party intermediaries) 

###  **Why we need customer information**

The information we request from customers allows us to provide a uniquely personal and customized online shopping experience. We may request information that we store for a customer's subsequent visits to Szul. This information enables us to do the following: verify customer identity so that we can authorize payments; ship orders to the correct address; contact customers regarding the status of their orders; allow customers to check the status of their orders, shipments, payments etc.; send customers information that is pertinent to their online shopping needs. 

We are committed to providing customers with the best online services so that they always have a safe and comfortable shopping experience. 

###  **How we collect and use customer information**

Currently, Szul gathers customer information -- such as names, billing address, and e-mail address -- to speed subsequent customer visits. Information is gathered during the ordering process. Some data may be used for Szul's marketing or promotional purposes. Szul does not share user information with any affiliates or partners. The information each customer provides to Szul is securely stored internally, and is not shared with any outside or third parties, except as outlined in this privacy statement (see "Third party intermediaries) 

The following items discuss in detail how we collect user information at different locations on the site and the purposes for which the information is used: 

####  **a) Order Form:**

Our order form allows a customer to create an account at Szul.com. We ask for contact information such as name, e-mail address, and shipping address. We also ask for billing information such as billing address and credit card number. We use this contact information to ship orders and to communicate updates about orders (i.e. order confirmation e-mail that includes a tracking number so the status of an order can be checked on the web site). We use billing information to bill the correct customer for products that have been ordered. If a customer chooses to send a gift, the recipient's information is used only once to send the purchase to the right address. Szul sends Registered Users promotional offers and discounts from time to time via an e-mail notification. If you choose not to receive additional information from Szul.com, simply click the "Unsubscribe" link upon receipt of your initial Newsletter/Offer. 

####  **b) Newsletter:**

Users can opt-out of receiving the newsletter if they no longer wish to receive it. In order to end a newsletter subscription, users must notify our customer service department via e-mail at customerservice@szul.com 

####  **c) Tell-a-friend:**

The "Tell-a-friend" feature uses the friend's e-mail address to send him or her a one-time-only e-mail about the site. No further communications will be sent. 

####  **d) My Favorites:**

The "My Favorites" area of the site allows customers to store favorite items they may wish to purchase at a later date. The information is stored entirely for the user's benefit: the site does not use this information for any other purpose. 

####  **e) Updating/Correcting user information:**

Customers may update or correct their information via the "My Account" section on the site. Customers may also request changes and updates by sending us an e-mail at customerservice@szul.com

####  **f) E-mail links:**

We use e-mail links located on the "Contact Us" page to allow customers to contact us directly with any questions or comments they may have. We read every message, and we try to reply promptly to everyone. This information is used solely to respond to customer questions or comments. We may file comments to use as we improve our site, products, and services, or we may review and discard the information. 

####  **g) Customize Jewelry Form**

We provide Customization Services and offer customers the ability to fill out a Standard Customization Form which is used to process their request(s). The information is used to respond to the customer's custom-made product request. We may file the form to use as we introduce new products to the site that may fit the customer's needs. We discard the information once we have met customers customization needs. 

####  **h) Sweepstakes Entry Form**

Szul.com offers a Monthly Sweepstakes which gives participants the opportunity to win a featured product. Applicants must register by entering their email address on the Monthly Sweepstakes Form. Each month, email addresses are collected and one winner is selected at random. The Sweepstakes Winner is contacted via email with instructions on how to redeem his/her winning prize. The registration form also includes an opt-in offer to receive additional Newsletters and Offers. All monthly sweepstakes participants have the ability to Unsubscribe to future promotions, at which time their identity is deleted and not included on any further distributions. **  
**

###  **Customer e-mail addresses**

All customers are required to provide a valid e-mail address. This address will be directly translated into a unique Szul ID (Customer ID) with which customers may log-on quickly and track their account status. This process also allows us to respond more rapidly to service requests, questions, or complaints. 

###  **Cookies**

Szul uses cookies to enhance the shopping experience on our site. Cookies are small amounts of data delivered to the hard drive via a web browser. The use of cookies enables Szul to process requests with greater speed, thereby providing a fast and easy shopping experience for our customers. 

We tie your personally identifiable information and order history to these cookies. Should customers choose to set their browsers to reject cookies, features such as Shopping Cart, My Account, and My Favorites will become inaccessible. 

###  **IP address usage**

When customers enter Szul's site, we automatically track their last visited URL, their next visited URL, the type of browser they are using, and their IP address. This data is collected in order to build site demographics, track user movement and use, expedite trend analysis, and administer the site. This is not tied to your personal information. 

###  **Third party intermediaries**

Szul promises not to share personal information with any third parties other than intermediaries involved in the process of completing an online transaction. Such intermediaries act as links in the order fulfillment chain and do not store, use, or retain any of the information we give them. Examples include credit card companies, authorization services, and banks. Please be aware that when you register for our Affiliate Program, you will be entering your personal information on our third party secured server site www.ssl.linksynergy.com. This page has the look and feel of the Szul site for ease of navigation back to our site. 

###  **Security policy**

In our effort to ensure safe and secure online shopping experiences, we wish to share information about our exhaustive user information protection and transaction security policies. 

####  **a) SSL Encryption:**

At any instance when a customer enters personal data while shopping or checking out of our site, we process the information via secure software technology to guarantee the safest shopping environment. When the customer is ready to check out from our site after making a purchase, a Secure Socket Layer (SSL) connection is invoked to transfer all sensitive data in a safe and secure way. The SSL encrypts the information, including name, address, and credit card number, so that unauthorized individuals cannot observe, decode, or misuse it as it is transmitted over the Internet. 

####  **b) Credit card protection:**

In the unlikely event that an unauthorized use of a customer's credit card is made while shopping at Szul, credit card companies limit card holder liability to $50. Szul promises to cover this $50 charge and to help customers to resolve the problem with their credit card company. 

###  **Changes to privacy policy and how we inform you of them**

Our privacy policy may be altered as we continue to develop our site and enhance our services. If there are any material changes to our privacy practices and policies, they will be clearly noted on this page. We shall also inform customers via e-mail of changes in our privacy policy, prior to making such changes. We encourage customers to review this policy periodically, so that they will be aware of improvements that further protect their privacy and security. 

###  **Customer commitment to this policy**

By patronizing our site, customers agree to the specific, aforementioned uses of personal information. Should a customer so desire, the customer may refuse future communications from Szul. In order to block communications from us, simply let us know via e-mail at [customerservice@szul.com](mailto:customerservice@szul.com) \-- we will honor all requests. 

###  **Szul's commitment to its practices and policies**

We are committed to adhering to and maintaining the highest standards of ethical practice on this site. Our policies are tailored to meet the specific needs and concerns of online consumers, and their security and privacy is our utmost priority. 

###  **Disclaimer**

Though we make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose personal information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on our Web site. 

###  **Contact Information**

If users have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at: 

Szul and its logos are registered trademarks of Szul Jewelry, Inc. All copyrighted logos are used with businesses’ permission.  
Copyright 1999-2014 Szul.com.
